# **Victor Aguilarte**

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Santiago de Chile (GMT-3) (+56) 9 3364 0485

<u>aguilartevictor72@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/victoraguilarte</u>

Frontend developer with 5 years of experience creating web applications, I have worked with various technologies such as **Angular, Typescript, JavaScript, Flexbox and bootstrap** and I have always focused on bringing the implementation of UX and UI to code, delivering on schedule. I'm passionate about continuous learning and always willing to find solutions to problems. My goal is to be part of an organization, where I can share and implement my acquired knowledge, a place where achievements and personal performance are recognized to continue growing as a professional.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

- 1. EY Chile Banco BCI Client, Senior Development (January 2024- Currently)
  - Responsible for the creation of new products to improve the experience of the bank's business users, improving it by 200%, which was reflected in the new feedback with customers. Developed in Angular under the **Single-Spa architecture**, allowing the creation of multiple **microfrontends**.
  - <u>Tech stack:</u> Angular (12, 15), TypeScript, API REST, Azure, GitHub, Veracode, Jira, Scrum.

## 2. EY Chile - Banco Bice Client, Senior Development (May 2023- December 2023)

- In charge of front migration of your COMEX products, for foreign trade. The products evolve by 300%, allowing their clients to have a friendly and intuitive UX where they can carry out their commercial operations.
- Tech stack: Angular (12), TypeScript, NodeJS, API REST, NestJS, Git, Bitbucket, Bamboo, Jira, Scrum.

## 3. NEORIS - Banco Santander Client, Frontend Developer (September 2021- May 2023)

- Responsible for the Front development of a Mobile app for the banking sector aimed at payments, collections
  and transfers of fiat money developed in **Angular** under **Module Federation and webpack** and deployed with
  a capacitor for IOS and Android. The user experience was improved by 200% and new users were registered to
  the product.
- <u>Tech stack:</u> Angular (8, 12, 13) FrontEnd microservices, TypeScript, REST API, Flexbox, Git, Azure, GitLab, Jira, Scrium

#### **4. SISTEMAS EXPERTOS, Computer Analyst** (June 2020 – September 2021)

- Responsible for bringing to code the new UX user experience embodied by the designers, improving it by 120% and making the project more intuitive for all users.
- We improved existing features and added some new ones to the application's operation that made it easier for users to use the system.
- <u>Tech stack:</u> Angular (9, 10) Angular Universal, TypeScript, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, REST API, Bootstrap V4.0, Git, **Scrum.**

## **5. ENVIROMODELING, Web developer** (January 2019 - June 2020)

- I was assigned the creation of a project under the Angular Framework oriented to the display of environmental data, improving the previous system by 300%.
- <u>Tech stack:</u> Angular (9), TypeScript, REST API, Flexbox, Git, GitLab.

# 6. PACIFIC LOGGING VENEZUELA, Frontend Developer (April 2017 – November 2019)

- In charge of the creation and development of the UX and UI, where dynamic and customizable dashboards were created to show the data received from sensors in the oil facilities. In the same way, representation figures were created, some in 3D that simulated the real values obtained and thus an improvement of 1,000% in visualization and data refresh rate was achieved. This was an innovative system that competed with others at an international level in the oil industry, since it optimizes the use of available bandwidth and allows a high level of customization for data visualization in the different components available within the system. (https://pacificlogging.com/site/rtdiller/).
- <u>Tech stack:</u> AngularJS, Angular (2, 4, and 5), REST API, THREEJS, Bootstrap, Flexbox, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, jQuery, MongoDB.

# **SKILLS**

**Programming languages:** Advanced: JavaScript, TypeScript; Intermediate: Python; Basic: PHP

Frameworks tools: Advance: Angular, AngularJS, Bootstrap; Intermediate: Django; Basic: Docker, NodeJS.

Agile: Scrum.

**Tools:** Git, Jira, Slack, Trello, Azure, GitHub, GitLab.

Database: Mongo DB, PostgreSQL.

**Languages:** intermediate: English; native:Spanish.

# **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSIDAD DE ORIENTE (UDO) - VENEZUELA, <u>SYSTEMS ENGINEER</u>, *JANUARY 2012 - 2019*